Andres Osorio . Jarvis Consulting

Recent Computer Science graduate with a background in Behaviour Analysis; I have experience in a wide variety of fields that have provided me with the right professional and personal skills needed to succeed in the Software world. 90% of all the data in the world has been created in the last 2 years; Data Engineering resonates with me because there is a need for qualified individuals to make sense of it all and I love both engineering and the patterns that arise from data. I am responsible, reliable, organized, disciplined, hard-working, fast-learning and goal-oriented.

Skills

Proficient: Java, OOP, JUnit, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, Maven

Competent: Rest APIs, Mockito, SpringBoot, C, Go, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/Node/Vue, Android Development

Familiar: Blockchain, Operating Systems, AI/Machine Learning, CyberSecurity

Development Projects

- Cluster Monitor: Developed a monitoring agent to keep track of a cluster's resources and usage across time; this provided the team invaluable information about decisions to scale the cluster (and each node in it) up or down. The project was implemented with Bash, PostgreSQL, SQL, and Docker.
- Core Java Apps: Implemented 3 projects using core Java:
 - Java Grep App: Searches for a text pattern recursively in a given directory and outputs matched lines to a file - implemented with Java 8 Streams.
 - **JDBC:** Performs fundamental CRUD operations using the DAO pattern as an abstraction layer with DTOs as the actual objects encapsulating data to and from the data source.
 - Twitter CLI App: Posts/shows/deletes Twitter posts via the Twitter REST API designed with the well-known MVC (minus V) architecture.

• SpringBoot App: In-progress

Cloud & DevOps: Not started

• Hadoop: Not started

• Spark/Scala: Not started

Note: All projects were tested using JUnit and Mockito.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis, Toronto (2020-Present):

- Worked in a small scrum team implementing Data Engineering projects
- Developed products successfully through continuous participation in scrum events
- Implemented projects using Java, Maven, SpringBoot, Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Git, Hadoop, Spark/Scala and Docker
- Implemented both Integration and Unit Testing for each project using JUnit and Mockito
- Used a Linux environment (centOS) for development

Social Worker, Community Living, Toronto (2015-2017):

- Worked in the TRE ADD (Treatment, Research and Education for Autism and Developmental Disabilities) program in a respite house
- Provided patients support with their daily activities (Hygiene, feeding and medication)
- Led recreational activities and behavioural programming to reduce problem behaviours and reinforce appropriate
 ones

ESL Instructor, Berlitz, Colombia (2009 - 2011):

- Taught English to students of all ages and levels
- Followed the company's dynamic and conversational teaching method and implemented it to my own approach
- Taught in one-on-one settings, as well as in groups ranging from 2-20 students

Education & Academic Projects

York University, Toronto (2017-2019), Bachelor of Arts, Computer Science

- Language Analyzer: Desinged and implemented 1) a small Java-like programming language and 2) its two associated functionalities: Java-like code generation and type checking. The project was developed on the Eiffel Testing Framework (ETF) Eiffel is an object-oriented and contract-based language. Implemented the project with the Visitor Design Pattern because it involves a language structure (classes, attrs, methods, etc.) that is meant to be closed for modifications and language operations (code generation and type-checking) which are open for modification this fulfills the open-close principle which is a requirement to apply the visitor pattern.
- Gym Platform: Developed a fully responsive Single-Page-Webapp that works as a platform to deliver instructional content on physical training and nutrition; it uses vue.js + materialize for the front end and node.js + firebase for the back end (authorization and deployment). It supports registering and logging-in/out (plans page is only accessible to logged-in users).

George Brown College, Toronto (2012-2015), Advanced Diploma, Behavioral Science Technology

• Behavior Modification: Successfully implemented various behavior modification programs at several placements (UHN, CAMH, Surrey Place, Community Living, elementary schools) under the supervision of assigned mentors. Continuously collaborated and communicated with supervisors at George Brown and placements to ensure positive results. The programs: 1) taught a new behavior, 2) increased desired behavior, and/or 3) decreased problem behavior.

Certificates & Awards & Activities

- Top 15% (2017 2019): Faculty of Electrical Engineering & Computer Science, York University
- Chair's Honour Roll (2017 2018): Department of Mathematics & Statistics, York University
- Dean's List (2012 2015): George Brown